<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Haris Ali - Product Human based in Edinburgh</title><link>https://haris.pm/</link><description>Recent content on Haris Ali - Product Human based in Edinburgh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 18:43:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://haris.pm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stakeholder management for product managers</title><link>https://haris.pm/posts/stakeholder-management-for-product-managers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 18:43:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haris.pm/posts/stakeholder-management-for-product-managers/</guid><description>Stakeholder management is a pivotal aspect of product management, serving as the cornerstone for ensuring product success and aligning with business objectives. As Product Owners or Product Managers, our role often extends beyond just managing products; it encompasses orchestrating a diverse array of stakeholder needs, expectations, and inputs. This task is vital as it directly influences our ability to deliver products that not only meet market demands but also align with organizational goals.</description></item><item><title>Disruptive Innovation Theory: Airbnb Case Study</title><link>https://haris.pm/posts/disruptive-innovation-theory-airbnb-case-study/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haris.pm/posts/disruptive-innovation-theory-airbnb-case-study/</guid><description>This article is a stripped-down version of an academic essay I’ve written on disruptive innovation theory and incumbent responses.
The 20th century experienced an advancement in the fields of science and technology that surpassed all the advancements of the centuries before. The rapid development in information and communication technology, the internet and global connectivity laid the foundation for electronic commerce: an industry that rapidly grew up to $29 trillion by the early 21st century.</description></item><item><title>Financial Technology 101</title><link>https://haris.pm/posts/financial-technology-101/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 22:23:37 +0500</pubDate><guid>https://haris.pm/posts/financial-technology-101/</guid><description>Former United States Secretary of the Treasury, Larry Summers said “the people who confidently reject all the innovation here in blockchain-based payment and monetary systems are on the wrong side of history,” as those who rejected the power of the Internet, and digital photography.
History has taught us that whenever a new technology or an innovation is presented, there is numerous opposition and rejection from those who stand to lose most from such transformative changes.</description></item><item><title>Analysis of Monzo through the lens of Entrepreneurial Ecosystems</title><link>https://haris.pm/posts/analysis-of-monzo-through-the-lens-of-entreprenurial-ecosystems/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 19:38:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haris.pm/posts/analysis-of-monzo-through-the-lens-of-entreprenurial-ecosystems/</guid><description>This article is a stripped-down version of an academic report I&amp;rsquo;ve written on fintech ecosystems and what role a keystone organisations plays in it.
Background This article analyzes Monzo – a challenger bank based in the UK to understand the business model and the role they play inside the ecosystem. The ecosystem analysis will be done through the lens of academic literature on business ecosystems to further understand the strategies behind the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Hello.</title><link>https://haris.pm/about/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 19:58:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://haris.pm/about/</guid><description>👋 Greetings from Edinburgh!
I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate Product and Technology Professional, thriving at the intersection of technology and business. My journey spans Entrepreneurship, FinTech, and Software Engineering, leading me to my current role as a Product Lead at LottieFiles.
🚀 My Transition to Product Management
What sparked my shift from engineering to product management? A profound fascination with the product development lifecycle. From engaging in problem discovery with customers to brainstorming innovative solutions and collaborating with engineers and designers, I am deeply involved in every step of creating remarkable products.</description></item></channel></rss>